Marty Glickman Interviews
Marty Glickman Interviews
1988-1991
Glickman, Marty, 1917-2001.
0.5 linear ft.
32 audiocassettes of Stan Isaacs' interviews with Marty Glickman and 5 audiocassettes of Glickman radio broadcasts. Glickman was an American sports broadcaster and commentator for more than fifty years; among other things he was known as "the voice of the New York Giants." Stan Isaacs assisted Glickman in the writing of his autobiography, The Fastest Kid on the Block: The Marty Glickman Story (1996).
2728914
Biographical History
Marty Glickman (1917-2001) was a Jewish American athlete, and a sports broadcaster and commentator for more than fifty years.
Glickman graduated from Syracuse University where he was an All-American football player; he later had brief careers in both professional football and basketball. He was a member of the U.S. Olympic team for track and field at the 1936 Summer Olympics in Berlin; for reasons never fully explained, he and Sam Stoeller, also Jewish, were replaced at the last minute in the 4 x 100-meter relay by two non-Jewish teammates and did not compete.
During Glickman's radio career he was "the voice of the New York Giants" from 1948 to 1971, as well as for the New York Jets (1972-1979, 1987-1989), the New York Knicks (1946-1970), and hosted pre-game and post-game shows for the (Brooklyn) Dodgers and the New York Yankees for 22 years. He also narrated news reels and served as commentator for a wide range of sports, from baseball to horse racing to lacrosse.
Glickman's honors and awards include the Naismith Basketball Hall of Fame’s Curt Gowdy Award (1991), the National Sportscasters and Sportswriters Hall of Fame Award (1992), and the American Sportscasters Hall of Fame (1993).
[Portions of this biographical sketch adapted from "MARTIN 'MARTY' GLICKMAN" on the International Jewish Sports Hall of Fame website, http://www.jewishsports.net/BioPages/MartyGlickman.htm.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Marty Glickman Interviews consists of 32 audiocassettes containing Glickman's reminiscences and recollections of his life and career, recorded by Stan Isaacs. Stan Isaacs assisted Glickman in the writing of his autobiography, The Fastest Kid on the Block: The Marty Glickman Story (1996). Glickman talks about growing up in the Bronx, his time at Syracuse University, his experiences at the Berlin Olympics in 1936, important sports figures such as Howard Cosell and Wilt Chamberlain, and more.
Also included in the collection are five audiocassettes of radio broadcasts, including several of Glickman covering New York Jets football games.
The item titles given in the inventory below are exactly as written on the tapes themselves, so some names or abbreviations may not be correct. Where possible, notes are included to clarify. Throughout, Glickman used the abbreviation "Anncer" for "Announcer".
Other Formats Available
All tapes have been digitized. Please contact the repository listed above for more information.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is in no particular order.
Related Material
See also the
Steven H. Scheuer Television History Interviews
for other interviews with Glickman.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radio, television, film; Auerbach, Red, 1917-2006.; Brown, Jim, 1936-; Cosell, Howard, 1918-1995.; Glickman, Marty, 1917-2001.; Holland, Jerome H., 1916-; Isaacs, Stan -- interviewer.; Leonard, Sugar Ray, 1956-; Stern, Bill, 1907-1971.; Wilkinson, Bud, 1916-1994.; New York Jets (Football team); Olympic Games (11th: 1936: Berlin, Germany); Tampa Bay Buccaneers (Football team); Athletes -- United States.; Jewish athletes -- United States.; Olympics -- Political aspects.; Sportscasters -- United States.; Audiocassettes.; Broadcasts.; Oral histories (literary works); Interviews.; Sportscasters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Stan Isaacs, 2005.
Inventory
- Recollections
  - Berlin Recollect, Living in Bronx-Brooklyn/Assignments thru (fors) to Singh and Ossie Solomon, 07/88; glickman_m-01 (Box 1)
  - Berlin Recollect Stoller 8-5-36 Meeting/Post Olym; Olym Parade; Early Track, 08/24; glickman_m-02; recollections of Glickman's Olympic Games experience in 1936 (Box 1)
  - Pro Grid; Early Radio; Jim Brown; Brud Holland/LeBon; Tennis; Cosell, 05/31/1989; glickman_m-03; Jerome H. "Brud" Holland, Howard Cosell (Box 1)
  - SA-Glick SYR; Dinner Recollect, Time Football/J. Brown End of 9/21/89 session T. Hucino; Director - Prod; Rizz-Kids, 09/21/1989; glickman_m-04; Marty Glickman recollects his experiences at Syracuse University (Box 1)
  - Berlin 1985 Incident; NYAC Dinner/End Berlin Incident; Begin Childhood, 02/05/1991; glickman_m-05 (Box 1)
  - (Clockmans) as a kid and OP; 3d side of Session to JRH-HS / Bert Lee Hockey; Marines; (Paley) Letter, Jim Brown; Marge Dancer, 02/05/1991; 02/11/1991; glickman_m-06 (Box 1)
  - Frosh Heroics SYR; Coll Commun (w/) Bench/ Syracuse Radio Show; Left off Olym-O Trial, 02/11/1991; glickman_m-07 (Box 1)
  - Start Hugh Carol to WHN acquires Dodger rites/Start Today’s Baseball, 02/18/1991; glickman_m-08 (Box 1)
  - Albert to Suggestions / Vandy to (Rubimach) and Russell, 02/18/1991; 02/26/1991; glickman_m-09 (Box 1)
  - Lord Burleigh to All Time College All Stars / Pro All Star Team to Bee-Holman Pro-Grid, 02/20/1991; glickman_m-10 (Box 1)
  - Rossides; IANT Games / Red Auerbach and Russell; Marty and Schenkel, 02/20/1991; 02/26/1981; glickman_m-11; Marty Glickman recollections; including comments on early NBA, Red Auerbach, Bill Russell (Box 1)
  - Marty with Eddie Andelman / Shenkel; Newsreels - Bill Stern, 02/18/1991; 02/26/1991; glickman_m-12 (Box 1)
  - 1st NBA meeting to Carl Braun / Contin. Carl Braun to Columbia, 03/05/1991; glickman_m-13 (Box 1)
  - 69 Rang - Nix HBO / David Black, 03/05/1991; glickman_m-14 (Box 1)
  - Joe Namath to Ray Leonard / Add Ray Leonard to Bob Trumpy, 03/13/1991; glickman_m-15 (Box 1)
  - Bradley to (Lanncer); Radio-TV Transition (Critiques) / Woody Allen Audit; Radio-TV Transition, 03/20/1991; glickman_m-16 (Box 1)
  - Camera Presence to Ryan Schenkel Analysis / Schenkel - McKay; Jackie Robinson, glickman_m-17 (Box 1)
  - Yonkers; Horse Named Go / Go Horse Story Castrated Balls to Bud Wilkinson, glickman_m-18 (Box 1)
  - Wilkinson to Mikan, glickman_m-19; Bud WIlkinson, George Mikan (Box 1)
  - Add Trumpy to Helen Stevens / LV Giants - Jets Start, glickman_m-20; correct spelling is Helen Stephens (Box 1)
  - Glickman / (Saperstein) / Glickman-Nix 45 Years Later, glickman_m-21 (Box 1)
  - (Spartak), AD, (Anncerless) Game, Jewish, Ken Wash, Tark / Jennings, Word Broadcaster, (Curr Sets), His Last Days, Jets, glickman_m-22; "Tark" may be Fran Tarkenton (Box 1)
  - First Loss; Gym Mates; Geog. of (Baskets); Family; Duffy; Dero; All Start; Wismer; Parker; Retire; Old Fogey, glickman_m-23 (Box 1)
  - More Wilt; Anncer Analysis; Harwell, AD 1936 Olym Scoring, glickman_m-24; Wilt Chamberlain (Box 1)
  - Mack Robinson / Mack Robinson II, glickman_m-25 (Box 1)
  - Garden - McCarver to K. Jason, glickman_m-26 (Box 1)
  - Marty on Basketball Origins / Early Football and House Man (Theme), glickman_m-27 (Box 1)
  - Marty at Fordham / Tips; Jets Misery; On Losers; Coslet (Conf.); Rangers; Pro-Grid; On Announcers; Part II as HouseMen/Local Network, glickman_m-28 (Box 1)
  - Marty on Anncer Tip Anecdotes / More Anncer Tip Anecdotes, glickman_m-29 (Box 1)
  - Albert on Glickman / Albert on Glickman; Glick on (Dennis) Byrd, glickman_m-30; "Albert" is Marv Albert (Box 1)
  - Marty G. Post Dennis Byrd / Side B blank, glickman_m-31 (Box 1)
- Sports broadcasts
  - Berlin - 1st Bdcast - Marge / Jets - Finale - Jewish - Garden - Anncers, glickman_m-32; Dennis Byrd (Box 1)
  - Glickman about 1988 Season End G - Jet Game / Post Giant - Jet Game Interview W/ Jim Gordon, glickman_m-33 (Box 1)
  - Glickman Jets - KC 1st Quarter / Glickman Jets - KC 3rd Quarter, glickman_m-34 (Box 1)
  - Glickman w. Mazer I / Glickman w/ Mazer 2 - Only the Beginning of Tape, glickman_m-35; "Mazer" is probably Bill Mazer (Box 1)
  - Jets - Tampa Bay End and Start / Jets - Tampa Bay 4th Quarter, glickman_m-36 (Box 1)
  - Jets - Rams / Side B blank, glickman_m-37 (Box 1)